There are two ways to start analyzing data in Tableau.
在 Tableau 中分析数据的方式有两种
You can either jump in and start exploring or you
你可以直接开始探索
can ask questions of your data and attempt to answer them.
也可以对你的数据提出问题 并尝试回答它们
We'll start by asking of this dataset, superstore.
我们先就 superstore 这个数据集提问
What are our sales like over time?
随着时间推移 销量是如何变化的？
If we simply double click sales and order date,
如果我们双击“销量”(Sales)和“订单日期”(Order date)
Tableau creates a timeline.
Tableau 会创建一个时间轴
And we can see our sales are increasing over time.
可以看到销量在随时间推移而增加
Note, that the mark type here says, automatic.
注意这里的标记类型显示为“自动”(Automatic)
We can change this to be another mark type if we wanted to.
如果我们想 我们可以将其更改为另一种标记类型
There's a bunch of mark types available to work with.
这里有一堆可用的标记类型
One thing to note is, if the mark type is automatic,
需要注意的一点是 如果标记类型为自动
it can change as you make changes to the view.
它可以在你更改视图时发生变化
Let's ask another question.
我们再提一个问题
What is the relationship between shipping costs and profit?
运费和利润之间有着怎样的关系？
This time, we're given what looks like the start of a scatter plot.
这次 我们得到了一个初步绘制的散点图
However, Tableau's aggregating our data,
但是 Tableau 对数据进行了汇总处理
the overall sum of shipping costs and the sum of profit.
即运输成本的总和和利润总额
So, we only have one mark.
因此我们只看到一个标记
We can bring in another field into the view
我们可以在视图中加入另一个字段
to change our breakdown of marks such as category.
例如“类别” (Category) 以更改分解标记的方式
If we encode category as color,
如果我们用“颜色”来编码“类别”
we see one mark for each category.
会看到每个类别对应一个标记
If we bring in another field like market to shape,
如果我们再加入另一个字段 例如“市场”(Market)
we get a mark per category per market.
则每个市场每个类别都会生成一个标记
The dimensions we add to the view,
我们添加到视图的维度
like category and market,
如类别和市场
define the number of marks that we see or the granularity at which we see the data.
定义了我们看到的标记数量或数据粒度
It's easy to change your mind about any variable that we encode.
对于任何需要编码的变量 改变想法很容易
For example, if we want to change color from category to order priority,
例如 如果我们要将颜色功能区的字段从 category 更改为 order priority
we simply drag order priority into the color shelf.
只需将 order priority 字段拖入颜色功能区中
Now we see a mark per order priority per market.
现在我们看到代表每个市场中每个订单优先次序的标记
If we want to make marks at a certain granularity but without encoding by color or shape,
如果我们要以一定的粒度生成标记 但不按颜色或形状进行编码
we can bring the field to the level of detail shelf.
我们可以将该字段放入 Detail 功能区中
It's important to know how adding dimensions to the marks card impacts the visual.
了解向标记卡添加维度对视觉效果的影响非常重要
And, the better you understand this,
你对这一点理解得越清楚
the more precisely you can build data visualizations.
创建的数据可视化图表就会越准确